Hey everybody, starting right off from
the end of our Laura data set creation
video.
Assuming you watched that. If not,
definitely go watch that first.
Otherwise, this video is not going to
make too much sense to you. The link
will be in the description to that. But,
starting off from there,
what you are going to do is head back
over to RunPod after downloading the
data set images and text captions that
we have just downloaded, which is at the
end of the video again.
Link in the description to that. Um,
video number one of this uh Laura data
set generation and Laura training video.
So, on RunPod, if you're going to head
right over to pods, and you are going to
come up to this GPU browsing section
here.
Um, for the Laura that we are training,
which is going to be a Z image
Turbo Laura, uh we are going to be using
the 5090, the RTX 5090. Um, this
probably shouldn't take you longer than
an hour and a half, maybe 2 hours at the
most uh with this GPU, so it's only
going to cost you a couple bucks,
probably less than three or four dollars
if this is your first time, assuming
maybe you make a couple mistakes.
But, we are going to go ahead and click
on the 5090 there.
Down at the template section, you are
going to change the template here, and
you are going to search for something
called Austris AI Toolkit.
There is a verified version of Austris
AI Toolkit, which you'll see in the
template selection down here. That is
the one that you want to use. Make sure
you click that one.
And you're going to head down to the
bottom here.
You can change a couple things here if
you want to um if you just want to be
safe, but I can guarantee that with 100
GB in each section here, maybe we just
keep that at 150 actually. Um, and
you're just going to deploy that GPU.
And then we're going to wait for all of
this to load. Um, it's going to take a
little bit for it to initialize and
stuff, so we'll be right back after
that's done.
All right, guys. After your pod is done
initializing, you're just going to click
on this port here, this HTTP service.
Going to click that, and it's going to
open up Austris AI Toolkit.
For the password, you are just going to
type in password.
Okay.
And you're going to see something like
this pop up. Now, this is the Austris AI
Toolkit. This is used to train Lauras.
Um, it's a wonderful wonderful tool.
First thing you're going to want to do
here is head over to data sets.
Okay.
Now, this is where you're going to
upload your data set that we have just
generated in the previous video. So,
assuming you have that already, which
you should. If you don't, please again
go watch that video. You're just going
to name this data set
anything. I'm going to name mine my data
set. Okay.
And you're going to see here that you
are now able to drag and drop images or
upload images to this
just drag them into this box here. So,
what I'm going to do
is I'm going to show you the output from
the previous video with all the dot txt
files
attached to them.
So,
what I'm going to do
is I'm just going to click on the very
top image here in the data set, and
scroll all the way to the bottom.
And I'm going to hold down shift, and
I'm going to click on the very last file
in this folder.
Now, again,
this I I showed you how to download this
data set after generating it in the
previous video, and it's going to
download as a zip file to your computer,
and you're just going to unzip it, and
then locate that unzipped folder with
all of this in here, and that's where
you will be able to access that. So, I'm
just going to drag and drop all of that
right into the Austris AI Toolkit.
And I will be right back when this is
done uploading. I'm going to show you
how now we can go through our data set
and weed out all of the images that we
think are not fit for our Laura
training. Things that you don't want,
such as, you know, maybe the face looks
different in this one, maybe the skin
tone is different in that one. We're
going to go through all of that and
figure that out.
All right, so all my images and their
associated dot txt files, the captions,
have been uploaded to the Austris AI
Toolkit data set section. What I'm going
to do now is I'm just going to go
through all of these, and I'm going to
get rid of things that I don't want.
Now, there's a few things that you guys
should keep your eye out for. Anything
that has obvious artifacts, which are
basically things that AI image
generation does sometimes that just look
wrong. So, a few examples of these are
obviously going to be extra limbs, extra
fingers,
weird, random, you know, things going on
with the face where like their eyeballs
are glowing or just weird stuff like
that. You're going to be the judge of
what you do and don't want in your data
set at the end of the day, and I'm just
going to I'm just here to basically
point out to you guys, you know, the
obvious things that you should get rid
of. Now, you can even go as far as
deleting things where the face looks too
AI-ish, or the body doesn't look exactly
how you want it to look, but I'm just
going to point out the obvious things
here. I'm not going to go through live
in the video and get rid of things in my
data set that I don't want in there
because there may be things that YouTube
doesn't like. Potentially. I'm not sure
if there is, but just to be safe, I'm
going to go through and weed out
everything
while I'm not recording, and you can
just pause the video and go ahead and do
that for yourself as well.
All right, guys. So, I've gone through
my data set, and I've gotten rid of a
bunch of images that I didn't want in
there. I can't stress this enough. This
is like this is this is 100% a quality
over quantity thing.
If you have like 20 to 30 images in the
end, that is fine as long as they are up
to your quality standards. Like I said,
quality over quantity. 80 images is not
going to train your Laura better if 50
of those images are inconsistent. It's
just going to make it worse. So, again,
quality over quantity. Once you've gone
through your entire data set and gotten
rid of all of the stuff that you don't
want, things that don't look right,
clothes that are clipping into the body,
or
just getting rid of all of the
artifacting pictures that just don't
make sense, and things that you don't
want also. You are going to now head
over to the settings
part
here.
And you're going to see that there is a
section where you can put in a Hugging
Face token. Now,
if you remember from the previous video,
you're familiar with Hugging Face tokens
at this point. So, what you're going to
do is we are going to head over to
Hugging Face
.com/settings/
tokens, or something like that. Again,
the link
to that will be in the description. I'll
put it in there for you. But, you're
going to want to log in here, so let me
log in real quick.
Okay, here we go. So, it is
huggingface.co/settings/tokens.
Okay, that is the link there. It's right
up there for you guys. And you're going
to click the create new token once
you've logged in. Um, you're going to
name this whatever, and then you are
going to want to make sure that you
check all four of these boxes under the
repository section. Those are the only
boxes you have to check, and then we are
going to create our token. And again, I
will be deleting this token after I'm
done with it here. So,
like I said the last video, don't know
what happens if you try and take that
token, but I'm not going to find out
token, so just don't do it cuz it's not
going to be there.
Anyway, moving on,
put your Hugging Face token into the
section here where it asks for it, and
then you're going to save the settings.
After you do that, we can now create our
Laura training job. So, you're going to
want to create a new job.
Okay, I have gone ahead and configured
every single setting within the
um
training job that we are making here.
So, the first thing that you are going
to want to change is the training name.
That'll just be the name of the Laura
files that you'll be downloading. The
trigger word, make sure that you create
a unique trigger word. This needs to be
a rendition of your character's name, or
something. Do not use common names,
everyday names. Use something unique.
Throw some numbers in there. This is
what you're going to be typing into your
prompting to trigger your Laura. So, it
needs to be unique. Can't use common
names, or it might get confused when
prompted.
Now,
I am doing a Z image Turbo for this
Laura, so I have gone ahead and selected
the Z image Turbo with training adapter
model here.
Um, I recommend that you do the same so
that everything fits in properly, and
you get the same results that I'm
getting.
I have low VRAM selected to on here. I
think it's selected on by default. You
just want to keep that on just to be
safe. You don't want to hit out of
memory errors.
You're going to keep everything here the
same. Coming over to the save section
here though, you want to change save
every to 100, and the max steps to save
to 10.
Okay.
Now,
I'm going to turn that down to one.
Batch size should be one. Everything
here should basically be set to what it
was by default. I don't think I really
changed much here. Don't turn anything
on.
Moving down to advanced, if you expand
this tab here, you will see do
differential guidance. I have this
turned on. This is recommended by
Austris, who is the guy who created this
Laura training tool here. So, I just do
what he says. He knows best, so keep
that on
or turn that on, rather.
And don't change the differential
guidance scale.
Now, coming down to the data set, this
all has been kept default here. The only
thing that I changed is the default
caption to my trigger word with followed
by a comma and a space. And moving over
to resolutions, these are all on by
default and this is all that we need
assuming that you followed the data set
creation in the previous video. 1024 and
768 specifically are the numbers that
you may recognize. We used those to
create our data set.
All right. Moving on. Samples.
So, you want to change sample every to
100 because we have it save every at
100, so after 100 steps, every 100th so
100, 200, 300, so on, all the way up to
3,000 if you decide to go all the way
with the training, but you probably
won't need to, honestly. Usually
somewhere around it really just varies
depending on how many images you have in
your data set, but somewhere around um
anywhere from 1,000 to 2,000, you should
have the Laura trained fully, but
back to what I was saying,
you're going to be saving every 100
steps and you're going to be generating
sample images every 100 steps. Now, you
want to keep the sample steps the same.
You don't really want to change much of
this. I have changed the height,
actually I think I kept the height at
1024, which is there by default, but I
changed the width to 768 to match our
data set resolution. Um just trying to
keep everything as close as possible
there. You want to turn on skip first
sample set. We don't need a sample image
for step zero. There's no point in
generating that.
Now, you want to come down to the sample
prompts. You're going to delete There's
going to be a bunch of default sample
prompts here. You want to click the X on
all of those. Just get rid of those.
Okay. And what I have done
basically is come over to Grok and
taken one of our captions that we have
generated in our data set. And I just
took one of them and I pasted it
straight into there and I said,
"Generate me four prompts with this
level of detail. One should be a
high-angle selfie. One should be an
eye-level selfie. One should be a
full-body POV from the front side
third-person image. And one should be a
full-body backside POV third-person
image."
And then I specified, "Make sure to
describe tight clothing in them and
change the setting for each prompt." So,
the tight clothing obviously, I'm sure
you can put it together that you just
want to be able to see how well the
Laura is training your character's body
based on, you know, your sample images,
so that's why.
And then I got these prompts here and I
took each one of these and I put them
into the sample prompts. Now, what I did
for each of the sample prompts is I
added woman followed by a comma and a
space at the beginning of each of them
because if you don't specify this, even
though your data set is trained on let's
say you trained a woman, for example,
like I did, you will still sometimes get
the opposite gender in your samples.
Even though that may happen, your Laura
is still training properly and you don't
need to worry if you forget to put woman
in the beginning of your prompts because
it because it is training properly
still. But, you just do need to specify
that still because
sometimes it just makes pictures of the
opposite gender.
All right. So, assuming that you have
just set all of those steps up the way
that I have, we are going to update the
job or create the job, right? And then
you should see something like this pop
up. Now, I had an error pop up
originally, but I went back and changed
a setting so that it doesn't
display that error anymore. What you're
going to want to do once you see this UI
pop up is just click the play button
here.
And that will trigger the
job and it will start downloading a
bunch of models and files.
As you guys can see here, we have some
pretty large models to download. We have
a 10 GB model and I don't know why mine
has stopped, but it'll probably resume
when it's done being
dumb. So, as soon as that's done, there
should be a couple more big Oh, there it
goes. There should be a couple more big
files that it needs to download and then
it should start the training process.
One thing I want to point out to you
guys while this initializes that you
might see in this terminal here that it
will get stuck on the
step missing keys. Well, it doesn't
really get stuck, but it it'll sit there
for a while and it is running and it is
working. So, if you see missing keys and
it's not moving for a while, just trust
the process. It is working. Just let it
move on to the next step. All right. So,
the way that you will know that your
training has begun successfully is that
you see here the name of your Laura in
the beginning and then you see
a steps out of 3,000, which should be
the amount of total steps that you've
configured your training to go.
And you'll see this number slowly going
up. Right now, mine's taking it It says,
you know, 1.5 seconds per iteration.
Yours may be quicker or faster. There's
a few things that will, you know, depend
on the speed, um but assuming that you
pretty much just copied my settings one
to one, you should be seeing a similar
speeds.
Now, every 100 steps, you are going to
stop training. Well, it's going to stop
training for you.
It's going to generate a checkpoint
here, which will be in the form of a dot
save tensors file, which you can
download.
Now, you don't want to download every
single one that you see,
but what you are going to do, which I
will show you here in a second, is every
100, it will stop. It will save that
checkpoint that I was just talking
about. And then over in samples, you
will generate as many images as you have
set for your sample prompts. So, in my
case, I did four. I recommend that you
probably do that as well. It doesn't
really matter. These are just samples um
basically showing you how trained your
Laura is. It's going to generate images
based on the training step. So,
the ones that you do want to download in
this checkpoint section here are ones
that look good in your opinion, look
trained enough for your model. So, let's
say, for example, at step 600, you have
a really good-looking result from
your samples here. It looks trained
enough. You are going to download the
step 600. Now, I recommend letting this
run for
more than what you think is good. So,
don't just download the first checkpoint
that you see and then stop the training
and close all of this out. You want to
let this run
past a few of the
air quotes good results that you get in
your samples and you just want to you
just want to let this run and see that
see maybe if it trains even more and
gives you better results.
All right, guys. So, I'm currently
almost on step 2700 here and I am going
to end the training process uh here in
the AI toolkit, but I just want to show
a
time lapse of these images. Here's step
1,000
from zero
going down
from 1,000 to 2,000. You will notice
that some of these look very different.
And I mean, it's pretty simple, guys.
Whatever step that you download in the
checkpoints here is basically more or
less the images that you're going to get
when you throw this Laura into a
workflow and start generating images for
yourself with that Laura.
So, you can download a few different
checkpoints and then throw them in a
Laura loader stack node in ComfyUI and
then change the strength. Say Say you
download four different ones and you do
0.25 on each one. Or you can download
the best one that you think is the best
and then just throw that into a Laura
loader at strength one and get the
resemblance from that Laura, you know,
that that single Laura. But, that's
going to pretty much wrap up the video
here. I will go all the way down here to
step 2600. You'll see that
for the most part
they look similar, but obviously I'm
going to download the one that I think
looks the closest to the character that
I'm trying to get.
And um you should definitely do the
same. Uh just go off of your best
judgment.
And uh yeah, guys. Thanks for watching.